Guide to the Harold William Thompson papers, 1942-1955.
Thompson, Harold William papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Harold William Thompson papers, 1942-1955.
14-12-649
Thompson, Harold William,
.8 cubic ft.
Correspondence, manuscripts, printed materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence with Louis C. Jones of the New York State Historical Association, and with Benjamin A. Botkin, Carl Carmer, Walter Edmonds, Ruth Rubin, Pete Seeger, and others contributing to or interested in the Quarterly, concerning its founding. Also, drafts, copies, and galley proofs of articles for the Quarterly; and hymns listed by composer compiled by Thompson while organist and choirmaster of the First Presbyterian Church, Albany. Also, a tape recording of ceremonies at a testimonial dinner honoring Thompson.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Musician, professor of English and American Literature at Cornell University, first president of the New York Folklore Society (1949-1950), and editor of the New York Folklore Quarterly (1950-1955).
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence with Louis C. Jones of the New York State Historical Association, and with Benjamin A. Botkin, Carl Carmer, Walter Edmonds, Ruth Rubin, Pete Seeger, and others contributing to or interested in the Quarterly, concerning its founding. Also, drafts, copies, and galley proofs of articles for the Quarterly; and hymns listed by composer compiled by Thompson while organist and choirmaster of the First Presbyterian Church, Albany. Also, a tape recording of ceremonies at a testimonial dinner honoring Thompson.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Thompson, Harold William, 1891-1964.; Botkin, Benjamin Albert, 1901-; Carmer, Carl Lamson, 1893-; Edmonds, Walter Dumaux, 1903-; Jones, Louis Clark, 1903-; Rubin, Ruth; Seeger, Pete, 1919-2014.; Cornell University.; First Presbyterian Church (Albany, N.Y.); New York Folklore Society; New York State Historical Association.
Titles:
New York Folklore Quarterly.
Subjects:
Folklore -- New York (State); Hymns.; Folklore; Hymns; Professors.; Musicians.
Places:
New York (State)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Correspondence
Arranged chronologically in original order; sometimes directly related to certain issues of the New York State Folklore Quarterly. There are also some manuscripts and galley proofs. Quotation marks indicate notations on folders.
Boxes 1-2
Series II. Manuscripts, drafts, galley proofs
Contain some related correspondence; in original order by Quarterly issues.
Boxes 2-4
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence
  - Quarterly Instructions, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - July 1944-March 1945, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - April-June 1945, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - July-September 1945, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - October-December 1945, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - March 1950, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Summer Issue 1954" April-December 1953, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "September Issue 1954" January-July 1954, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "September Issue 1954" August-December 1954, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - January-September 1954, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - July-December 1954, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "Spring Issue 1955" January-December 1955, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "June 1955" Summer Issue February-May 1955, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "June 1955" Summer Issue June-September 1955, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "Winter Issue" January-August 1955, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "Winter Issue" September-December 1955, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Series I. Manuscripts, drafts, galley proofs
  - "Spring 1954", 1954 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "Summer 1954", 1954 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Autumn 1954, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Winter 1954 Part I, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Winter 1954 Part II, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Spring 1955 Part I, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Spring 1955 Part II, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Summer 1955 Part I, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Summer 1955 Part II, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Summer 1955 Part III, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Summer 1955 Part IV, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Autumn 1955 Part I, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Autumn 1955 Part II, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Autumn 1955 Part III, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Autumn 1955 Part IV, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Winter 1955 Part I, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Winter 1955 Part II, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Winter 1955 Part III, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - "Catalog of Anthems listed by Composers", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 8)